Iris (Xiaobi) Pan

Product Designer

Address Santa Clara, CA - Open To Remote Work

Phone (617) 899-7188

E-mail irisxpan@gmail.com

WWW thisiris.github.io (password_magic)

Iris Pan is a **strategic** and **interdisciplinary designer** with **9 years'** experience **leading omni-channel product design and innovation** from start to finish. Coming from an **Engineering + Design + Tech** background, she is able to dissolve boundaries between different fields, blend the **digital with physical**, and use constraints as fuels for **creative problem solving**.

Iris has been recognized as a leader in exploring how **new interface technology**, **human-centered design and storytelling** together can engage people at a deeper level.



Education

Aug 2017 - Harvard University

May 2019 Master in Design Studies (Tech Focus) - Cambridge, MA

Feb 2018 - MIT Media Lab

May 2019 XR, Design Innovation, Tech Entrepreneurship - Cambridge, MA

Sep 2008 - Zhejiang University

Jun 2013 Bachelor of Engineering (Industrial Design Major) - Hangzhou, China



Work History

Nov 2021 -Current

Lead Product Designer / Alation

CA, USA

- Oversee the Data Governance part of Alation's ecosystem. Design strategic visions, new UX features and execute at a pixel level with 2 other designers.
- Help Alation elevate their design excellence and overall user experience through leading workshops and building design-led product innovation pipelines.

Aug 2019 -Nov 2021

Sr. UX Design Engineer / Mastercard Labs

New York, USA

- Led R&D in New Interface + New Commerce Experience Innovation: created XR/ IOT demos to explore new
 customer touch points and business opportunities, including Mastercard Virtual Unattended Store, VR New
 Payment demo, Quantum Settlement System... 4 patents filed and exhibited at global tech summits.
- Co-led Large Scale Cross-Functional New Product Development: 3 products launched to date, including Mastercard Blockchain-Based Smart Contract Platform, B2B Payment Ecosystem Redesign, Empower: Online Marketplace Analytics Solution, etc. Ran design workshops and presented to sr leaderships weekly. Iterated and produced design deliverables within tight timeline.
- Rapid UX Prototyping for Internal Incubator Projects: created the first couple of prototypes for Mastercard Priceless Planet Coalition and other social-impact driven projects.

Apr 2017 -Jul 2017

Sr. UX Designer / CI&T

Shanghai, China

- Designed the **ChickVacc app** for Merial Animal Health Ltd. Enhanced poultry farmers' work efficiency with **30% increase** in chicken vaccination rate.
- Redesigned the official website for global digital solution company CI&T. Helped them elevate brand image and win major clients like Coca-Cola China.
- Provided Lean + Agile UX Consultancy on behalf of CI&T China for clients such as HongKong PolyU.

Nov 2015 -Nov 2016

Interaction Designer / COC (A Creative Agency)

Shanghai, China

- Invented a first-of-its-kind hybrid retail experience, Love Cassette, that combines in-store human-machine
 interaction with online personalized-content sharing to achieve a seamless interaction + business loop.
 Toured nationally with multi-million visits and profits.
- Created a **double-player Kinect game** for **Bosch**'s product launch campaign with **100k+** offline participants and online sharing in a month. Increased sales by **30%**.
- Originated a **gesture-based interactive experience** for client. Featured by Asia Design & Management Forum (**20k visits/3 days**). Client's search rate raised by 50% and sales doubled.

Nov 2012 -Nov 2015

Designer / Freelance

Shanghai, China

 Delivered omnichannel brand and UX design solutions for 10+ mid-sized Chinese companies to help differentiate their brand and expand customer base. Established design consistency across various platforms (e.g. web, app, video, prints, physical store...).



Skills



UX Design & Prototyping, Design Thinking, Iterative Design, Storyboarding



Game Design, ARVR Design & Development (Unity + Unreal), Computational Design, C# programming



Industrial Design, 3D Modeling, Digital Fabrication, Electrical Design & Engineering, Robotics



Sound Design, Animation, Video Production, Branding, Motion Graphics, Web Design



Honors



- 14th International Conference on Design Principles & Practices Invited Speaker 2020
- Apple Hardware Technology Group Guest speaker 2019
- IEEE GEM (Games, Entertainment and Media) Conference Speaker & Panelist 2019
- New England Graduate Media Symposium Speaker & Panelist 2019
- A' Design Award Generative, Algorithmic and Parametric category Award Winner 2019
- Red Dot Concept Design Award Award Winner 2011